John E Dlugosz

Westminster, CO 80021 • (C) 661.993.7720 • Jedlugosz@gmail.com • linkedin.com/in/john-dlugosz/

Professional Profile

Data Analytics: Extracted data from various sources, including databases, manual files, and external websites. Created Ad Hoc reports to present to senior management status of programs. Query departmental data to show current inventory of test hardware.

Process Improvement: Enacted numerous projects to improve interdepartmental processes and created viability to order status, order tracking and distribution Point of Contact in an automated fashion. Business liaison to IT, manufacturing and engineering to provide functional requirements on tool development.

Budget and Forecasting: Negotiated and preserved project budgets for procurement and implementation of test equipment needed for daily engineering test operations. Used utilization data of prior programs to determine projected needs for future programs.

Corporate Training: Created, implemented, and maintained a full training curriculum for new employees. Leveraged industry-leading solutions including numerous Microsoft Office suite components to create Standard Operating Procedure, which was successfully utilized across all levels of organization from senior management to subject matter experts.

Work Experience

Qualcomm, San Diego, CA

Project Analyst – Coordinator (11/2016 to Present)

- Forecasted and allocated projected global inventory for test equipment required for engineering testing.
- Collaborated with Project Managers to collect and submit forecast for budget approval for new projects.
- Extracted department data from corporate tools to provide weekly test equipment allocations to Project Management.
- Used advanced data mining functions to pull data from separate data bases into a single spreadsheet and generate Ad Hoc reports to present to upper management.
- Extracted data sets with ~40,000 lines to conduct high level analysis to present to upper management.
- Oversaw million-dollar lab recycling efforts to reuse phone screens in manufacturing of new hardware.
- Managed the training of 2 distributors well ensuring current projects continue to run smoothly.
- Extracted department data from management software to run analysis on aging inventory.

Project Analyst - Distributor (11/2015 to 11/2016)

- Distributed internal hardware from stockroom with 600+ devices valued at \$2.5 to \$5M.
- Managed shipping logistics for test hardware to domestic and international internal teams.
- Implemented change in storage of internal hardware improving space efficiency in the stock room by 50%.
- Used corporate tools to procure \$1M worth of accessories for engineer testing needs.
- Identified and developed organizational performance metrics used to improve department processes.
- Created reports and presented to leadership and Project Management on quantities of test equipment to ensure program needs are meet.
- Planed and designed pivot tables, decision trees, charts and graphs for analysis by upper management.

World Pack USA, San Diego, CA

Business Analyst (12/2014 to 11/2015)

- Managed client database, including client information and prioritizing client needs.
- Collaborated with the IT team to improve database functionality and organization.
- Reported to the Sr. Customer Service Manager providing financial information including daily margins and data entry status.
- Identified innovative solutions for improving database functionality, reducing data entry time by ~5 hours per week.
- Formulated new email templates in response to emergent client issues.

Data Entry Associate (01/2014 to 12/2014)

- Processed and input 100s of new orders into corporate system, handling check and credit card numbers.
- Operated with a Service Level Agreement that work is to be completed within 24 hours of receipt.

Education and Certificates

General Economics - Bachelor of Science Degree, 2015

San Diego State University- College of Business Administration, San Diego, CA Program Focus: Quantitative analytics, Qualitative analytics, and Regression Analysis

Professional Skills

Software Applications

SQL, Tablaeu, Qlikview, Microsoft Office Suite, SharePoint, Microsoft Visio, Visual Basic Scripting, Salesforce, Agile